Welcome everybody for this exciting
session about demystifying the new
Microsoft copilot chat in Business
Central.
As you know the new Microsoft copilot
chat to come to all our users with this
release and we are absolutely excited
about it. It brings lot of magic power
and capabilities. And today what you
want to do you wanted to do to demestify
to look under the hood and understand
how internal things are built. So when
you going to use it or show it to your
customer you have a full trust
understanding and really know how things
look behind the scene. And that's the
purpose of our today's session. the way
how we're going to approach it. Uh
Abdul, we're going to show you some of
the scenario, some of the power and
magic which copal chat can bring to you
and your customers and then we're going
to debrief what has happened and look a
little bit deeper to understand how
things are working behind the scene.
>> Abdul go.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Uh hey everyone,
my name is Abdulat Khan and I'm a
software engineer in Business Central.
So today I'm going to show you a few
queries in copilot and uh we will see
how copilot reasons over that. We will
see how copilot brings in the data from
business central and also from the web
to basically end up answering the user's
query. Okay. So here I have on my
machine uh the business central open and
the copilot pane is also open on the
side and uh I'm going to try a query
something like uh tell me about my top
five items in my inventory as per price
per unit and convert it to Danish crone
using the latest exchange rates. So
let's see what happens. So as you can
see we have submitted the query. Copilot
has started reasoning over it and it's
going through the business central data.
You can see the progress messages as
copilot reasons over this. Okay. So here
you can see I looked up your items list
in business central and sorted it by
unit price descending. So basically the
item that has the largest per unit price
that's the one that we want and we want
the top five of those. Right? So we get
a really nice table over here and we get
a bunch of citations over here that you
can actually click on and it will open
that particular item in the business
central pane. Okay. So that was one part
of the query. The other thing is the USD
and the Danish crone conversion rate
that you see over here that is also
pulled from some web source. And this
last column that you see here is
calculated by taking the data from your
business central and the exchange rate
information and and just giving that
unit price in Danish crown. So that's
really awesome uh that you know it was
able to uh bring together information
from multiple sources and and uh give
you this really nice response. So let's
do a little something else. Let me show
you one more query. So I'm just going to
type out a query which is uh really
simple and like very vague. tell me
about S 100.
So I don't need to type out the full
name of that particular item, right? I
just I just said tell me about S100 like
you go and figure it out for yourself,
right? And as you can see, uh Business
Central tools have the ability to
basically resolve that S100 to S100
semi-automatic. That's that's a thing
that I was looking for. And you can see
this beautiful response coming in. We
have the number of units. We have some
basic details. We have a bunch of
citations over here. And that's
basically all the information that it
was able to give. Okay. So just to
summarize what we did here, you can see
the reasoning steps of Business Central.
You can see the data coming in from
Business Central. You can see the data
coming in from a web source. And along
with that, we also tried out a second
query where you saw this uh vague query
being successfully resolved and a
beautiful answer coming through. Um
okay, that's uh what I wanted to show
you. Um if back to you like let's hear
from you like what else have you got for
us? Come on.
>> Uh thank you Abdul. So you just seen a
fantastic demo how a copilot can bring a
lot of data from different sources
obviously from business central but some
suddenly in from web and this is one of
the power kind of the journal
intelligence which we're giving to you
with this release but how does it really
work you know how does it really work
that's the main question let's reflect
on this today so first of all we have a
question and user in our case was Abdul
he asked with a question he want to know
some item data by by local currency and
things like that. So we have this
message but in the same time his second
question was in a conversation. So we
bring a message a conversation to
copilot before we can give you a right
answer on your question. Now maybe you
didn't really notice but on the second
demo uh Abdul was on a item card. So we
can also pull that content from UI. If
you're on a given page, maybe you're on
a given page of your installed
extension, we can pull this data to
copilot to hint a little bit what needs
to happen because maybe you're in a
context of work and you want to take it
from there. We can also bring knowledge
about you, maybe your role, maybe what
do you do and all this help us to send
this data to a pilot which will
hopefully can help us to find a right
answer on your question.
The first thing will compiler do is it
will try to understand what has to
happen and you have this step called
intent detection. Basically it's saying
given the history and messages what
should be the answer for a question
which Abdul had and the way how we going
to appro approach it now it's very
different how maybe uh previous
integration of chat working business
central instead of doing this kind of
one time attempt to find the right
response we're going to go through
something which is called aentic loop so
copilot going to iterate through a
number of tools uh with all the power it
have to answer that question. In our
particular demo, you've seen how Copilot
could access business central data
through something which we call business
central tools. You also seen how copilot
can could bring more information maybe
from your work data, maybe from your
calendar, maybe from your outlook, maybe
from your shareepoint.
Capilot can also go ahead and maybe talk
to another agent which you can build
with different Microsoft tools. So it
has a lot of options where to search for
also the web as we mentioned to find the
right answer and once it went through
this loop try multiple iteration finally
happy with the response is it something
we should consider to show to our users.
Now the user want to have a clear uh
answer. So of course we'll come back
with a message and the message has to be
grounded in reality because we want to
verify maybe double check where the data
is coming from. If you give you your top
sales, if you give you a discount, if
you give you some filtered view of the
list, we want our user to always
reconfirm with their own or his own eyes
where the data coming from. And it's not
just like a poor text. You've seen we
can make you a very rich output. We can
show you charts. We can show you tables.
We can show you like a very beautiful
representation of data in any context
like conversation exactly as you and me
would expect in a modern in the modern
age when you work with capilot.
And of course there was one small small
part which you've seen in Abdul demo.
Copilot will always come back with
suggestions. Basically Abdul had a
conversation about items and item and we
always come back with a suggestion what
can we ask more what is the next step to
do maybe to explore more data or take it
from here so it's not just kind of one
shot prompt and response now you have a
true conversation and you continue to do
it talking in the context um of a data
in a in a business central so this is in
a shell how the machinery it work behind
the scene and now we would like to cover
a little bit more specific questions
which could come to your mind as you
hear for us explaining all that. So this
is our favorite part.
Every time we do this demo, everyone in
the audience will have a question and we
would like you to walk through some of
the questions and making sure you have a
crystal clear answer how things are
working. So I'll take a first question
and the first question is does Microsoft
Copilot respect permissions?
And there is only one answer here and
the answer is it does. It absolutely
does. Every time you run a copilot, it
runs as you. For example, every time you
ask a pilot information about business
central, about tables or data, it will
be always run in your boundaries. So for
example if Abdul would like to
understand what is gene salary uh
because he doesn't have permission to
that there is no way on earth will be
able to answer this question. So that's
exactly how should be uh Microsoft
copilot run as a user and it's
fundamental principle how we build a
copilot in Microsoft.
>> So one of the questions uh that we get
asked quite a lot is uh can I control
who has access to Microsoft copilot? Can
I control which people in my
organization have access to copilot? And
obviously the answer is yes, you can.
You can fully control who has access to
it in your organization. So you can see
here on the slide that there is a
copilot and agent capabilities page
where you can opt in or opt out of AI
features and uh the admins should agree
to those terms and yeah this this is
something beautiful. You are in control.
You have this view where you can control
who or what copilot capabilities are
enabled. Yep. Over to you, Guinea.
>> Another tricky question can be it's all
fantastic, but how Microsoft Copilot
really retrieves data from Business
Central like what is this technology
behind the scene? And the answer is it's
a the same technology we use to build
all agentic integration around Business
Central. It's a Microsoft Business
Central MCP server.
I encourage you to go ahead to this link
ak.ms/bcmcp
and learn more about the capabilities
and all the cool stuff you can build
with MCP server and we have a number of
session for this recordings through our
colleagues from Kenny from Damian uh go
ahead and learn more about Microsoft MCP
now the benefit of going through the
technology stack behind a scene is that
now Microsoft copilot has access to all
the tables and all your data which you
have in your environment. This may
include data from your installed
extensions from your customizations and
you don't really need to build any
custom APIs in order for Copilot to get
access to the data. So basically
all your extensions all your
customizations we can go ahead and
reason over it. So you can go ahead
start a conversation ask a data question
and it will just work out of the box. It
just works for you as you would expect.
Now if you're an ISV who builds those
extension for our customers and you
would like to learn what is the best
guidelines to uh build my extension in a
way so copilot have an easier job to
work with it maybe how to make it more
descriptive maybe how to understand how
to provide those small things here and
there so agents can work better with my
extensions. We have a absolutely
fantastic
uh Microsoft learn article. So please go
ahead and learn and read that.
>> Next up uh this is uh another question
that we get asked quite a lot. Can I as
a user trust copilot responses? Do I
know that they are accurate or not? So
the answer is that uh you get a copilot
answer but along with the copilot answer
you get a bunch of citations. So the
small pills that come up in the response
you can click on those pills and you can
open up the required content in the
business central pane. So you can see
whether the the response that copilot
cited is correct or not. You can double
check that. And at the same time, we
have richer user experiences to show you
uh the citations. We have the user
experience to show you the progress
messages as I showed you in the demo.
And using all of that, you can sort of
cross-check and double check that
whether the copilot produced answer is
accurate or not. So we have all these
affordances in place. Uh another thing
is that uh at the end of your response
you might see a sources button and when
you click on that you can see all the
things that copilot saw all the things
that copilot cited. So the things that
the AI saw as well as the ones among the
things that it saw that it cited. So
these are the affordances that that we
provide for you to be able to judge the
accuracy of the copilot response. Yep.
Exactly. So, we don't want you to guess,
we want you to verify and be confident
that the response are exactly what
you're looking for.
>> The next question we're getting and we
just absolutely love this question. How
can you help us to make Microsoft
Copilot better in Business Central? And
the easiest ways for you to do it is to
go ahead and provide a feedback directly
to Microsoft Copilot.
We love your feedback.
Uh you can go ahead and click the small
thumb up button for example if you like
or enjoy what capilot come up with you.
You can also share a lot of information
if you would like provide extra content.
You can share your uh screenshot you can
share if you wish to do it uh all your
prompts and more context data which will
be very very helpful for us to
troubleshoot some of the issues or maybe
if you want to express that hey in this
case I expected something else. It's a
fantastic opportunity for us as a
product group to learn from your
experience. So go ahead, provide your
feedback to Microsoft. We'll love it.
That's how we're going to make it better
and better. And with that, we would like
to thank for your time and we hope
you'll find the session useful today.
>> Yep. Thank you. Thank you so much.